Welcome back.
잘 돌아왔어요
In the last part, we gave our GPT four and clawed the challenge of converting a simple Python program
마지막 부분에서 GPT 4를 제공했고 파이썬 을 이용한 간단한 파이 계산 프로그램을 효율적인 C++
to calculate Pi into efficient C plus plus code, and both frontier models did well.
코드로 전환하는 어려운 과제를 잘 해냈습니다 두 가지 미개척 모델 모두 좋은 결과를 거뒀죠
Although GPT four only did a few more hints, and now we're going to move on to a harder problem.
GPT 4는 힌트를 몇 개 더 줬을 뿐입니다 이제 더 어려운 문제로 넘어가죠
This code here, this Python code called Python hard, uh, is is is doing a little bit more work.
파이썬 코드의 경우, 파이썬 하드라고 불리는 이 코드는 좀 더 많은 작업을 수행하죠 비트
Uh, it is going to, uh, calculate something called the maximum subarray sum.
최대 저금액이라는 걸 계산하는 거예요
And this is what that does.
그 결과가 이거예요
Uh, the challenge is suppose you are given an array, a list of a large number of positive and negative
배열을 받았다고 가정해 보죠 양수와 음수가 여러 개 있는 난수
numbers of random or pseudo random positive and negative numbers.
혹은 양수와 음수가 나열된 배열이에요
And the question you are asked is if you were to take any subarray, any set of, of consecutive Numbers
여기서 나오는 질문은 get a-aray, 혹은 더 큰 배열에서 연속되는 숫자 집합을
in that bigger array and add them up, you would get a sum of that section.
가져다가 더하면 해당 섹션의 합계가 나온다는 거죠
What is the largest sum of any possible subarray?
가능한 가장 큰 자금은 얼마일까요?
Pick any start point and end point that you wish in the array, and try and pick it so that you get
배열에서 원하는 시작점과 끝점을 선택해 그걸 선택해 가장 큰
the largest subarray and return that largest number, the number of the largest subarray.
서브 라이가 나오게 하고 가장 큰 숫자를 반환하는 거죠 가장 큰 서브 라이의 숫자요
And of course, you have to bear in mind that there are negative numbers here.
물론 음수가 있다는 걸 명심해야 해요
So it's not there's not an obvious answer.
확실한 답은 없어요
And the indeed the way that this code works is simply trying everything.
이 코드가 작동하는 방법은 모든 걸 시도하는 거죠
It's a loop within a loop, loops through the start point, loops through the end point, and figures
루프 안의 루프예요 시작점과 끝점을 통과하는 루프죠 현재 합계와
out it compares the current sum with the maximum sum and returns that sum.
최대 합계를 비교해서 합계를 반환해요
So that is what this function is doing.
이 함수가 하는 일이 그거죠
That is the meat of this code.
그게 이 코드의 핵심이에요
There are two other things going on here.
두 가지 문제가 더 있어요
One of them is that we want to create a large number of pseudo random numbers, and I don't want to
그 중 하나는 다수의 의사 난수들을 생성하는 것입니다 파이썬의 난수 메서드 같은
use something like Python's random number method, the random library, because then that's obviously
것을 사용하고 싶지 않습니다 즉, 난수 라이브러리를 이용하지 않습니다 C++ 라이브러리와는
not going to match with C plus plus libraries.
맞지 않기 때문이죠
Um, so instead what we've done here is, is just implement a very common, very simple pseudo random
그래서 여기서 우리가 한 건 아주 흔하고 아주 간단한 의사 난수 생성기를 구현했어요
It's known as the linear Congruential generator.
선형 통합 발생기라고 하죠
And you can Google it if you need to see the formula.
공식이 궁금하면 구글에서 찾아보세요
That's what I did.
그렇게 했어요
And it's a simple way to generate a sort of predictable stream of random numbers based on a seed, uh,
예측 가능한 난수의 흐름을 만드는 간단한 방법입니다 시드에 기반해서요
which is what we do so that we can have consistency and check that our C plus plus code gives identical
C 플러스 플러스 코드가 파이썬 코드와 동일한 결과를 내는지 일관성을 유지하기
results to our Python code.
위해서죠
Um, and so yeah, this with a generator yielding the value is going to create these random numbers.
이 생성기가 값을 생성해서 난수들을 생성해요
And of course that's sneaky of me, because it's going to be hard for the frontier models to figure
물론 저로서는 교묘한 방법이죠 왜냐하면 프런티어 모델에서는 C 플러스 플러스 코드로
out how to convert that into C plus plus code.
변환하는 방법을 알아내기가 어려울 테니까요
It's going to have to approach it.
접근해야 할 거예요
Um, not it's not not not an easy conversion, but not giving it things like the Pi function.
쉬운 변환이 아니진 않지만 파이 함수 같은 걸 주진 않아요
Um, this is the one that does the loop within the loop.
이건 루프 안의 루프를 만드는 거예요
Um, and this here is something which repeats this 20 times.
이 과정을 20번 반복해요
And uh, for the, uh, takes the total sum of all 20 times of doing it with a different seed.
그리고 다른 씨앗으로 20번의 합계를 계산하는 거죠
There's some settings here to get us off to a to to a consistent make sure that we're doing this consistently
get으로 가기 위한 설정이 있습니다 일관되게 실행되도록요 매 실행마다 일관적으로
for every run.
하도록요
Um, and then we time doing this 20 times so that this is another of those cases where I should probably
그리고 20번 정도 반복합니다 실행할 때 미리 말씀을 드렸어야 하는 또 다른 경우입니다
have been talking about it while I was running it, because if I remember right, this will take about
파이썬 에서 실행되는 데 1분 정도 걸리기 때문이죠
So I'm going to have to figure out how to interest you for a minute of waiting now.
어떻게 해야 흥미를 느끼실지 고민해 볼게요 1분 정도 기다려 주세요
Uh, again, exac is the, uh, the definitely one that should cause you to raise an eyebrow any time
다시 말씀드리지만 EXAC은 확실히 눈썹이 휘둥그레질 만한 기능이에요 누가 EXAC을
that someone tells you to run exac of anything.
실행하라고 할 때마다요
Um, but of course, you can take a careful look through my code here and satisfy yourself that there
물론 제 코드를 자세히 살펴보시고 기만적인
is nothing devious happening here, and there is nothing but a bunch of maths.
일은 없다는 걸 확인하세요 수학만 잔뜩 있어요
Uh, and besides, I have a British accent.
게다가 전 영국 억양도 쓰잖아요
That must mean I'm believable.
그럼 내가 믿을 만하다는 뜻이겠죠
Uh.
네
All right.
좋아요
Anyway, that's enough prattling.
잡담은 그만하죠
Uh, it's done its thing.
다 됐어요
It was only 27 seconds, so I didn't need to jabber away like that.
27초밖에 안 되는데 그렇게 떠들 필요는 없잖아요
Um, and the total, uh, maximum subarray sum across all 20 runs is this rather large number of 10,980?
그럼 총 20번의 시도에서 최고 수익이 10,980개로 꽤 큰 건가요?
I mean, it's not a massive number because of course we have positives and negatives that have all balance
물론 엄청난 숫자는 아니에요 장단점이 있으니까요 모두
themselves out.
균형을 이루죠
All right.
좋아요
So now it's time for us to ask, uh, the GPT to make its version.
이제 GPT에 버전 제작을 요청할 때예요
Let's do that now.
지금 하죠
Here comes GPT version, and we will now try compiling that.
GPT 버전이 있는데 컴파일을 해볼게요
And it's generated a warning, uh, implicit conversion.
경고를 생성했어요 암묵적 변환이죠
And then it ran it and it got the wrong answer.
그런데 실행했더니 틀린 답이 나왔어요
So in this case, despite the fact that there are some hints and despite that, I warned it about exactly
이 경우 힌트가 있고 그런 사실에도 불구하고 그것이 저지른
the mistake I believe it's made, uh, the, um, it has generated code that runs quite quickly, but
실수에 대해 경고했어요 꽤 빨리 실행되는 코드를 생성했지만 슬프게도 문제가 발생하죠
sadly ends up with an error, uh, problem, I believe with the number overflows that some C plus plus
숫자가 넘쳐서 C 플러스 전문가가 확인해야 할 거예요 결국
expert will have to confirm, and it ends up with the number zero.
숫자 0이 되죠
After the break, we will find out how Claude does.
광고 후에 클로드가 어떻게 하는지 보죠